NISHANT DESAI

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT



+14317267152



mishantdesai1306@gmail.com



Vancouver, Canada



https://nishantdesai1306.github.io/

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

CGPIT, Uka Tarsadia India, May 2016

XII

T. & T. V. Sarvajanik High School India, May 2012

Χ

T. & T. V. Sarvajanik High School India, May 2010

SKILLS

- React
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Express
- React Native
- Flutter
- HTML
- Javascript
- CSS

PROFILE

I'm a full stack developer with 5+ years of experience in developing web apps as well as mobile apps. I like to keep looking for new patterns, technologies and libraries for various frameworks which will help me in increasing my knowledge base.

Moved to Canada as a PR in June, 2022.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK ENGINEER

FoodX Tech, Canada | Sept 2020 - Sept 2022

FoodX Technologies builds eGMS software platform to manage their online grocery demand.

- Worked on a React based web application which lets users manage orders and products online.
- Designed UI/UX solutions based on what's more feasible for a given task.
- Took lead in designing multiple company wide features and their implementation.

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Modd.io, Canada | Jan 2018 - Sept 2020 (Worked remotely)

Modd.io is a web based IO game editor which not only allows users to join multiplayer online games but also allows them to build and deploy their own games without any prior coding knowledge

- Worked on a React based web application which lets users build their own multiplayer game.
- Reduced S3 costs by 50% through a two-tier caching system.
- Designed and built a provisioning and communication system among servers which is horizontally scalable.
- Hosting games and Auto-scaling games on game servers to provide smooth UX.
- Deploying private servers for users to create a new game session where only people with invite links can join in.

JR. APPLICATION DEVELOPER

JumpByte, India | Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

- Developed multiple Web applications based on AngularJS, MEAN stack, MeteorJS.
- Built several native Android apps.
- Collaborated with team-member to plan and develop robust solutions.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Gold Medalist of my batch in college
- Secured 3rd rank in Robo race at GTU Zonal Techfest held at SCET in 2014
- Secured 1st rank in Coding Master event at SCI CLONE 2K14 organized in our college
- Secured 2nd rank in FixIt (Finding error in programs and to rectify them) at SCI CLONE 2K14organized in our college
- Secured 1st rank in Robo race in Techfest held at FETR, Bardoli

INTERESTS

- Anime
- Documentaries
- Tech
- Movies

PROJECTS

FoodX eGMS - Suite of multiple web apps which help in managing the inventory, processing and delivery of orders to end users.

Modd.io - A Web App which would allow users to play different multiplayer games as well as creating them (without any prior knowledge of coding) and making it live so that other users can play that game. Its front end is built using a combination of React + EJS and the backend is built using NodeJS.

Coordinate - Web App developed using MEAN stack which helps in assigning and managing tasks to subordinate employees.

JumpPush Server - An Angular Meteor web App which helps in integrating services like Email and Push notification to an existing Mobile/Web App.

PewDiePie vs T-Series - Flutter based mobile application which shows live subscriber counts for PewDiePie and T-Series it also allows users to share screenshots of current subscriber count and it also features a dark mode.

PewDiePie vs T-Series Lite - Lite version of PewDiePie vs T-Series, this is also a Flutter based mobile application which shows live subscriber counts for PewDiePie and T-Series but it has less features, this was my submission for Flutter's create contest.

SmartCopy - Mobile application which keeps record of all copied texts and User can access them using a floating window.

SmartCopy Web - MERN based web app companion for SmartCopy android app to sync items copied in your phone to the web and access them seamlessly from any device.

Chattz - Chatzz offers basic functionalities like registering users for chat apps, sending messages, getting notifications about change in user status, change in message status (i.e. send and read).

Lost and Found - MEAN2 based web app, it is place for people to post images of lost items that they've found in case the owner of those items is searching for those items, This app also has chat functionality (Chatzz framework) so that the owner can discuss place and time to get the their lost belongings back with the person who has uploaded the image.

Pinger - Mobile application which helps in getting immediate responses from other users by displaying a call like screen with user specified message on it.

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated herein above are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief

Date: 11th October, 2022 Nishant A. Desai